David López Espada

Personal Info

Email

DavidLEspada@gmail.com

Phone

722392080

Skills

Unreal Engine

C++

Engine tools programming with C++ and Python

Unreal Engine modern systems like GAS and CommonUI

Code and blueprint debugging

GPU, CPU and Memory profiling

Animation programming

Team leadership and coaching

Reliable teammate

Software

Unreal Engine

Visual Studio

JetBrains Rider

PyCharm

Blender

Draw.io

Languages

Spanish



English

Hobby/Interest

- Videogames
- Playing keyboard
- Table Tennis
- Robotics
- Graphics Programming

Unreal Engine / C++ Game Programmer with three years of experience leveling up daily.

I started working in the video game industry in 2020. I started developing prototypes and developing VR apps to now leading demanding projects.

I have a passion for everything related to problem-solving in development, from gameplay to animation, AI and tools, having experience in each area.

Work History

2022-11

Lead Programmer

- present

Pentakill Studios. Valladolid

Developed some core architecture of the project such as:

- Gameplay framework in C++ using Gameplay Ability System.
- UI system using CommonUI for the Main menu, Pause menu and Settings menu.
- An event system solution called "Consequence System" for managing all kind of gameplay events in a modular way.
- The animation locomotion logic of the player.
- Adapted SPUDs Save System.
- Developed engine tools for artists, game desginers and other programmers.

I also lead a team of programmers where I:

- Review code and help getting the best solution.
- Manage pipeline tasks and programming production issues.
- Coach intern programmers and new employees.

2022-08 - 2022-11

Gameplay Programmer

Pentakill Studios, Valladolid

Development in a next-gen first person horror video game, working with 10+ developers and in charge of Gameplay Programming.

2021-01

- 2021-05

Unreal VR Developer

FrameOver, Valencia

Main programmer in an standalone experience for Oculus Quest 2 developed in Unreal Engine.

- Installed SDKs and responsable for app builds and compatibility
- VR interaction systems
- UI navigation
- Android profiling for optimal FPS

2020-10 - 2021-01

Junior Game Programmer

FrameOver, Valencia

I developed a prototype of a video game using blueprints, prioritizing efficiency mixing quick and useful solutions.

Education

2019-09 - 2020-06

Videogame Development, Master in videogame development

PrimerFrame, Valencia

Project at the end of the course.

2012-09 - 2018-06

Highschool

I.E.S San Pascual, Alicante